chapter 2.
So I lived my life alone, without anyone
that I could really talk to,
until I had an accident with my plane in
the Sahara Desert six years ago.
Something had broken down in my engine.
And since there was no mechanic or any
passenger with me I decided to carry out
the difficult repairs myself
It was a question of life or death for
me
and scarcely enough drinking water to
last for a week.
The first night, then, I went to sleep on
the sand,
a thousand miles away from any human
habitation.
I was more isolated than a shipwrecked
sailor on a raft in the middle of the
ocean.
Thus
you can imagine my amazement, at sunrise,
when I was awakened by an odd little
voice.
It said
please--
draw me a sheep!"
"What!"
"Draw me a sheep!"
I jumped to my feet, completely
thunderstruck.
I blink my eyes hard and look carefully
around me.
And I saw an extraordinary small boy who
stood there watching me very seriously
Here you may see the best portrait that
I was able to make of him later
But my drawing is not quite as charming
as its model.
That, however, is not my fault
I had been discouraged by grown-ups in
my painter's career when I was six years
old, and I never learned to draw anything,
except boas from the outside and Bowers
from the inside.
Now I've stared at this sudden
apparition with my eyes fairly starting
out of my head in astonishment.
Remember, I had crashed in the desert a
thousand miles from any inhabited region.
And yet my little man did not look like
a child lost in the midst of the desert
nor to be fainting from fatigue or
hunger or thirst or fear
and at last I managed to speak, I said to
him:
"But--
what are you doing here?"
And an answer he repeated softly and
slowly, as if he was speaking of a matter
of great consequence:
"If you please--
draw me a sheep..."
When a mystery is too overpowering, one
dare not disobey.
Absurd as it might seem to me, a thousand
miles from any human habitation and in
danger of death,
I took out of my pocket a sheet of paper
and my fountain pen.
But I suddenly remembered how my studies
had been concentrated on geography,
history, arithmetic, and grammar,
and I told the little chap (a little
Crosley too)
that I did not know how to draw.
He answered
That doesn't matter
please Draw me a sheep..."
But I had never drawn a sheep before
So I drew for him one of the two
pictures I had drawn so often.
It was that of the boa constrictor from
the outside.
And I was quite astounded to hear the
little fellow greet my hat like picture
with,
"No, no, no no I don't want an elephant
inside a boa constrictor. A boa
constrictor is a very dangerous creature,
and an elephant is very cumbersome.
Where I live, everything is very small
draw me a sheep.
Draw me a
sheep."
So then I drew a sheep
He looked at it carefully and said:
"No.
This one is already very sickly.
Make me another
and I made another drawing.
My little friend smiled gently and
indulgently
don't You see that is not a sheep
it is a ram. It has horns."
So I made another drawing
But it was rejected too
like the others.
"This one is too old.
I want a sheep that will live a long
time."
By this time my patience was exhausted,
because I was in a hurry to start taking
my engine apart as soon as possible
So I tossed off this drawing.
And I threw out an explanation with it
that is only the box. The sheep you asked
for is inside."
I was very surprised to see a light
break over the face of my young judge:
"That is exactly the way I wanted it!
Do you think the sheep will have to have
a lot of grass?"
"Why?"
"Because where I live everything is very
small..."
"There will be surely enough grass for
him," I said I'm giving you a very small
sheep
He bent his head over the drawing:
"Not so small that--
Look!
He has gone to sleep..."
And that
is how I made the acquaintance
of the little prince